Guide to the Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records TAM.630
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records
2011-2013
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Roberts, Amy
Occupy Wall Street. Archives Working Group.
TAM.630
145.5 Linear Feet in 33 oversize flat boxes, 15 flat file folders, 19 custom boxes, 4 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, 2 media boxes, and 1 oversize tube box
51 Megabytes in 47 graphics
1 sound disc (cd)
The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group was created in October 2011 by Amy Roberts and Jeremy Bold to collect and preserve material related to the Occupy Wall Street protest in the fall of 2011 in Manhattan, New York. The Archives Working Group (AWG) continued to collect materials related to other Occupy protests in 2012 and 2013, as well as climate change and racial justice protests. The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records document protests by the Occupy movement between 2011 and 2013, and the work of the AWG to collect materials from these protests. The collection also documents the beginning of the AWG through mission statements, draft budget proposals, meeting agenda, and minutes. The bulk of the collection documents the first Occupy Wall Street protest in the fall of 2011 in Zuccotti Park in Manhattan through posters, artwork, fliers, clippings from print and online news sources, letters of support, diaries, born-digital photographs, buttons, textiles, organizational documents, and the movement's newsletter, The Occupied Wall Street Journal.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction, with the exception of textiles, select artwork, and signs larger than 24" x 36".
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Amy Roberts of the Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group, 2013, 2017, and 2019. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2013.010, 2013.022, 2017.048, 2017.077, and 2019.079. Materials associated with the collection were found in repository in April 2014. The accession number associated with this material is 2014.096.
Appraisal
In 2017, duplicate fliers and periodicals were deaccessioned.
In May 2018, the following materials were deaccessioned from the collection: foam letters, clothing, drums and drumsticks, candles, markers, heat blankets, and zip-tie handcuffs. Also removed were posters with duplicative, general, or personal messages; abstract artwork; blank cardboard; and extremely dirty or damaged posters.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged by type of document. The container list is arranged in alphabetical order.
Posters collected on specific dates are listed in chronological order by collection date, with descriptive information about each sign included in the inventory. Posters without a documented date of collection are not arranged, but are housed according to size and material type.
Discussion documents are arranged in alphabetical order by discussion topic. The remaining organizational documents are not arranged, but are housed according to size.
Historical Note
The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group was created in October 2011 by Amy Roberts and Jeremy Bold to collect and preserve material related to the Occupy Wall Street (OWS) protest in the fall of 2011 in Manhattan, New York. The Archives Working Group (AWG) was created to enable the movement to document itself and ensure that materials from the movement would be made available to the public. The AWG collected records of the movement in all formats, and documented the decisions of the OWS General Assembly, Spokes Council, and other working groups. The AWG continued to collect materials related to other Occupy protests in 2012 and 2013, as well as climate change and racial justice protests held in New York City during those years.
Custodial History
Materials were collected by Amy Roberts of the Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group in 2011 and transferred to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives in 2013 and 2017. Materials associated with collection were found in the repository in April 2014 and were accessioned at that time.
Scope and Contents
The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records document protests by the Occupy movement between 2011 and 2013, and the work of the Archives Working Group (AWG) to collect materials from these protests. The bulk of the collection documents the first Occupy Wall Street (OWS) protest in the fall of 2011 in Zuccotti Park in Manhattan, New York. Other documented events include climate change and racial justice protests in New York, Massachusetts, and Pennsylvania. Materials include posters, ephemera, artwork, correspondence, clippings, periodicals, diaries, a map, a compact disc, digital photographs, notebooks, organizational documents, and periodicals.
The bulk of the collection consists of material collected by members of the AWG in order to document the New York City Occupy protest in 2011. The majority of this material consists of posters and ephemera created by members of the movement in Zuccotti Park in 2011. In addition to the posters and ephemera, the AWG also collected letters of support, artwork, clippings, periodicals, diaries, notebooks, digital photographs, a map, and a compact disc. The posters and ephemera document the main issues of the movement, in particular income inequality, wealth distribution, and the influence of corporations on the government. The ephemera includes fliers, pamphlets, clippings, textiles, buttons, and stickers. The letters of support were sent by friends and family of the protestors, supporters from across the country, and one seventh grade social studies class in New Jersey. The clippings include articles from print and online news sources about the protest. The periodicals include the movement's publication, The Occupied Wall Street Journal and Occupy!, which includes articles written by members of the movement and other activists and was published by the n + 1 foundation. The artwork includes small and large-scale plywood, masonite, drywall, metal, and fabric paintings, sculptures, and props created by members of the protest. These items include messages similar to the posters and ephemera. The diaries contain personal entries and meeting notes created by unidentified members of the Occupy movement. The notebooks were found in Zuccotti Park after a raid on the protesters by the New York Police Department in November 2011 and collected by members of the AWG. The map is of a route the protestors may have used in lower Manhattan, in the area surrounding Zucotti Park. The digital photographs depict protesters and police officers, and the compact disc contains the song "People's Park".
Material documenting the AWG is physically housed with the organizational documents and includes mission statements, draft budget proposals, meeting agenda, minutes, and notes. The bulk of the AWG records consist of notes taken by Amy Roberts at AWG meetings, with other material consisting of budget proposals presented to the OWS General Assembly and notes on collecting oral histories and archives best practices.
Material documenting the work of the General Assembly and other working groups are also physically housed with the organizational documents. These include a draft vision statements, a "Declaration of the Occupation of New York City", meeting agenda and notes, discussion documents, informational signs, and notes taken by Roberts at working group meetings. In addition to the AWG, the Music Working Group and other unspecified working groups are documented in the collection. The discussion documents consist of large, rolled sheets of paper with a general topic of discussion and related topics written on the paper.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Textiles, select artwork, and signs larger than 24" x 36" require conservation treatment before they can be made available to researchers.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Occupy movement -- New York (State) -- New York.; Protest movements -- United States.; Picket signs.; Printed ephemera.; Roberts, Amy; Occupy Wall Street (Movement)
- Artwork
  - Artwork -- Abraham Lincoln with phrases, 2011; cuid902; 1 item one painting (Item TAM.630.cuid902)
    Paintings (visual works)
  - Artwork -- Apes diptych, 2011; cuid901; 2 items two signs (Item TAM.630.cuid901)
    Works of art.
  - Artwork -- Banker stencil, 2011; cuid903; 1 item one sign (Item TAM.630.cuid903)
    Picket signs.
  - Artwork -- The Cover Up, 2011; cuid897; 1 item one painting (Item TAM.630.cuid897)
  - Artwork -- The Cover Up, 2011; cuid898; 1 item one painting (Item TAM.630.cuid898)
  - Artwork -- The Cover Up, 2011; cuid899; 1 item one painting (Item TAM.630.cuid899)
  - Artwork -- The Cover Up, 2011; cuid900; 1 item one painting (Item TAM.630.cuid900)
  - Artwork -- Crisis Chaos Change, 2011; cuid895; 1 item one painting (Item TAM.630.cuid895)
  - Artwork -- Donation box (The Peoples Bank of Change), 2011; cuid1626; 1 item one sculpture (Item TAM.630.cuid1626)
    Scope and Contents
    Artist: Albert Wilking
    Sculpture (visual works)
  - Artwork -- Kitchen, 2011; cuid890; 1 item one sign (Item TAM.630.cuid890)
    Information signs.
  - Artwork -- Krishna, 2011; cuid905; 1 item one painting (Item TAM.630.cuid905)
  - Artwork -- The Land of the Free..., 2011; cuid892; 1 item one sign (Item TAM.630.cuid892)
  - Artwork -- More Like A Fail Out!, 2011; cuid889; 1 item one sign (Item TAM.630.cuid889)
  - Artwork -- 99%ER, 2011; cuid893; 1 item one sign (Item TAM.630.cuid893)
  - Artwork -- 1,000,000,000,000, 2011; cuid904; 1 item one sign (Item TAM.630.cuid904)
  - Artwork -- Rise Sir Lapdog Revolt..., 2011; cuid896; 1 item one painting (Item TAM.630.cuid896)
  - Artwork -- Small donation box, 2011 (Box 38)
  - Artwork -- Statue of Liberty with cut out at face, 2011; cuid1094; 1 item one poster with cut out at face (Item MSS.630.cuid1094)
    Posters.
  - Artwork -- Tentacles, 2011; cuid13389; 1 item tentacles with rods and strings to move tentacles (Item TAM.630.cuid13389)
    Costume components.
  - Artwork -- Top hat with flowers, 2011; cuid13388; 1 item one hat (Item TAM.630.cuid13388)
  - Artwork -- Umbrella with painted flowers, 2011; cuid13390; 1 item one umbrella (Item TAM.630.cuid13390)
  - Artwork -- When The Well's Dry..., 2011; cuid891; 1 item one sign (Item TAM.630.cuid891)
  - Artwork -- Why I Embrace Change..., 2011; cuid894; 1 item one painting (Item TAM.630.cuid894)
- Artwork, buttons, patches, 2011-2013 (Box 1, Folder 1, Box 4, Folder 10)
- Annotated map of Lower Manhattan, undated (Flat-file-folder 15)
- Clippings, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Compact disc, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Diaries and notebooks, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 4, Box 4, Folder 16-18)
- Digital photographs, 2011; cuid15271; 51 Megabytes 47 graphics (Box Electronic records, Object TW_TAM_630_ER_1)
- Flag, 2011 (Flat-file-folder 3)
- Fliers, stickers, and postcards, 2011-2013 (Box 1, Folder 5-13, Box 2, Folder 23, Box 4, Folder 1-4, Folder 10, Box 36, Folder 13-21)
- Letters of support, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 14-23, Box 4, Folder 5-8)
- Map of lower Manhattan, 2011 (Flat-file-folder 9)
- Object -- Tax Dodgers 1% Foam Finger, 2011; cuid34929 (Box 39)
- Organizational documents, 2011-2013 (Box 2, Folder 1-17, Box 4, Folder 11-14, Box 5, Box 11, Box 17, Box 18, Folder 1-3, Box 19, Folder 1, Box 29, Box 31, Box 35, Folder 7-8, Box 36, Folder 10-12, Box 39, Flat-file-folder 1, Flat-file-folder 2, Flat-file-folder 4)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Action tactics, 2011 (Box 42)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- [General discussion of movement and its short- and long-term goals], 2011 (Box 48)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Internal coordination, 2011 (Box 43)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Interoccupation communications coordination, 2011 (Box 47)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Narrative message, 2011 (Box 50)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Other, 2011 (Box 43)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Outreach and growth, 2011 (Box 49)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Shared values principles, 2011 (Box 46)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Social and political wins impact, 2011 (Box 41)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Trust relationship building, 2011 (Box 44)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Visioning process strategy long term thinking, 2011 (Box 45)
- Pamphlets, 2011-2013 (Box 2, Folder 18-19, Box 4, Folder 15, Box 36, Folder 22-24)
- Periodical -- The Occupied Wall Street Journal, 2011-11; cuid34928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Periodicals, 2011-2013 (Box 2, Folder 20-22, Box 3, Folder 1-4, Box 19, Folder 2, Box 34, Folder 11)
- Poster collected on October 24 -- New survey shows majority of NY'ers support Occupy Wall Street..., 2011 (Box 10)
  11" x 17" White paper with black and red ink, taped to cardboard.
- Poster collected on October 24 -- Show me the $, 2011 (Box 9)
  18.5" x 26.75" Brown cardboard with gold paint.
- Poster collected on October 24 -- Day 1er leaving today to organize other occupations need $$ for smartphone, 2011 (Box 9)
  20" x 23.75" Brown cardboard with black and green marker.
- Poster collected on October 24 -- Occupy Wall Street spends $4,000 a week on photocopies but still cannot buy a coffee machine that keeps the protesters warm, happy and ready to protest, 2011; cuid34933 (Box 10)
  15.25" x 19.5" Brown cardboard with black marker.
- Poster collected on October 24 -- Image of Lloyd Blankfein as vampire drinking the blood of the Statue of Liberty, reads "Enough prosecute Goldman Sachs personhood", 2011 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  14.25" x 22" White poster paper with black marker, and white paper with black ink taped to poster, and silver shoelace. Verso reads: Enough of the vampire squids wrapped around the face of humanity...
- Poster collected on October 24 -- The top 1% controls 40% of wealth, 2011 (Box 9)
  20" x 30" White foamcore with blue, red, green, and black marker. Verso reads: The bottom 40% controls 1% of wealth
- Poster collected on October 24 -- Health care for the 99%, 2011
  25.75" x 26.25" Brown cardboard with black and red marker. Verso reads: Health care not wealth care
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Child safe zone, 2011 (Box 27)
  7.5" x 18" Brown cardboard with black ink and red duct tape.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- A corporation is like a dyslexic Robin Hood, 2011 (Box 27)
  10" x 18" Brown cardboard with red ink.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Life, liberty, and the pursuit of humanity! 99%, 2011 (Box 27)
  14" x 18" Brown cardboard with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Corporate power is big government!, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  9" x 15.75" White cardboard with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Occupy UES Do it now!, 2011 (Box 27)
  9.5" x 18.5" Brown cardboard with red marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Hey! At least North Dakota's hiring!, 2011 (Box 27)
  9.5" x 18.5" Brown cardboard with blue marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- There were ninty and nine that safely lay in the shelter of the fold but one was off on hills away buying up all the gold, 2011 (Box 10)
  14" x 20" White paper with black marker on brown cardboard.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Restore American Airlines flight attendants' wages, 2011; cuid34934 (Box 10)
  17" x 19" Brown cardboard with red, green, and blue marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- When I play, I draw [Monopoly Commmunity Chest card] When you play, you draw [Monopoly Commmunity Chest card] Why does it feel like we are drawing from different decks?, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  22" x 28" Orange poster board with black marker and yellow paper with black ink. Verso reads "Corporation: an engenious device for obtaining individual profit without individual responsibility - Ambrose Bierce"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Give donations to official working groups only, 2011 (Box 28)
  23" x 25.5" Brown cardboard with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- No left, no right, only 99%, 2011 (Box 39)
  Diameter = 13.5" Blue painted wooden circle with black marker. Verso reads "I don't wanna get locked up but if that's my only choice then so be it!"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- 99% stealing is wrong Cadogan Scimecca 5 years old, 2011 (Box 39)
  Diameter = 13" Blue painted wooden circle with black marker. Verso reads "Do you love yourself or others best?"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- One good way to control greed is to > wages, 2011 (Box 39)
  Diameter = 13.25" Blue painted wooden circle with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Instead of asking for debt forgiveness, 2011 (Box 39)
  Diameter = 13.25" Blue painted wooden circle with black marker. Verso reads "Stop paying your bills!"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Sick of big banksters greed + arrogance? Then leave em'! Go with small/local banks + credit unions, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  11" x 14" Yellow poster paper with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- What do Americans want? Fair pay for hard work, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  11" x 17" White poster paper with red marker. Verso reads "What do banksters want? Freedom to loot
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Eat trees Please pardon our appearance. We are making the world! Feet!, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  11" x 17" White paper with black ink and green marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- We are the other 99%, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  12" x 18" Blue poster paper with white and red ink.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Hungry?, 2011 (Box 27)
  13.25" x 15.5" Black styrofoam with white paint. Verso reads "Eat the rich!"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- You have a gambling problem..., 2011 (Box 27)
  13.5" x 16.5" Black foamcore with white paint. Verso reads "...We're here to help!"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Justice is blind, 2011 (Box 27)
  13" x 16.5" Black foamcore with white paint. Verso reads "... Not stupid!"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Forget where the money went..., 2011 (Box 27)
  13.5" x 15.5" Black foamcore with white paint. Verso reads "...Where did it come from??"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Bail me out! Only $25,000, 2011 (Box 27)
  13.5" x 15.5" Black foamcore with white paint.
- Poster collected on November 6 -- Health care is a human right, 2011 (Box 33)
  18.5" x 21" Brown cardboard with red and blue marker.
- Poster collected on November 6 -- Wall Street you're fired, 2011 (Box 33)
  18" x 19" Brown cardboard with white paper, black ink, blue and red paint, and blue tape.
- Poster collected on November 6 -- Give 2 the people! The G.A. is an evil super power!, 2011 (Box 28)
  7.5" x 30.5" Brown cardboard with white, red, and yellow paint.
- Poster collected on November 6 -- Image of black and white American flag with person lifting one of the stripes, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  20" x 30" White poster board with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 6 -- Image of person climbing street sign, which reads "Worth fighting for", 2011 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  20" x 30" White poster board with red ink.
- Poster collected on November 6 -- Image of pig, which reads "That's some pig!", 2011 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Poster collected on November 6 -- 99% how many more do we need?, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  22" x 28" White poster board with brown, red, black, and green paint.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- The Fed-Treasury evil axis rips us all off!, 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  8.5" x 11" White paper with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- We are in a drastic need of ending the exchange of us bonds..., 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Racism is strictly forbidden here!!, 2011; cuid34935 (Box 27)
  17" x 19" Brown cardboard with purple marker.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Shrewd Uncle Sam..., 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Wanted Kathleen Ann Corbet, 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  8.5" x 11" White paper with black ink. Verso reads "Wanted Lewis S. Ranieri"
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Image of girl lying on street in front of protesters with "Occupy for innocence", 2011 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  13" x 19" White poster board with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Turn off the news + read!, 2011 (Box 27)
  13" x 18.25" Brown cardboard with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Elmo hates Wall Street, 2011 (Box 28)
  20" x 29" Brown cardboard with black, brown, and yellow marker.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- First in the nation caucus occupation..., 2011 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  11" x 17" White poster board with black ink and silver duct tape.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Wanted Stanley O'Neal, 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Wanted Sanford "Sandy" I. Weill, 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Capitalism Capitalism Capitalism..., 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Image of a bull surrounded by protesters and bankers, reads "The brazen, brazen bull", 2011 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  14" x 22" Tan paper with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Image of worker confronting evil Uncle Sam, reads "Occupy for freedom peace truth love life", 2011 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  19" x 24.75" White poster board with red and blue paint.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- We, Tamils support Occupy Wall St., 2011 (Box 33)
  12" x 22.5" Brown cardboard with blue marker and twine.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Image of worker confronting evil Uncle Sam, reads "Occupy for freedom peace truth love life", 2011 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  19" x 24.75" White poster paper with blue paint.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Give us back Manhattan, 2011 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  12.5" x 20" Green paper with black ink and blue duct tape.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Money money money no longer funny in a rich mans world, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  12.5" x 20" Green paper with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Int'l. Action Center Occupy Wall Street, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  11" x 17" Yellow paper with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Image of one-eyed Uncle Sam, reads "Stop! These changes are only mandated for your safety, convenience and security!", 2011 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  18" x 24" Grey paper with red paint.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Image of two hands, reads "Place your hand here. Have stranger place hand here. Remove hands when no longer strangers.", 2011 (Box 33)
  18" x 24" White particleboard with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 9 -- OWS Screen Print Guild..., 2011 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  12" x 18" White paper with black ink, laminated.
- Poster collected on November 9 -- This system has no future for the youth the revolution does! Revcom.us, 2011 (Box 16)